Charlie Beswick

Arborist, Estate Maintenance, Hard & Soft Landscaping

Dorchester DT1 charliebeswick96@aim.com 07802 366404

Hello!

To whom it may concern,

Hi, my name is Charlie and i currently live in Dorchester! I'm currently looking for part-time or fullemployment. I'm a driven individual, with a lot to gain, and I'm looking for an employer that's keen to put me to the test and give me the opportunity to prove my worth.

What I can bring to the Team.

I value myself as a Team player and I'm always looking for cohesion and unity within a group. I'm literate, and have strong people skills which I feel makes both teamwork, and communication with the public/clients, an area that i excel in.

As an employee my focus's would be primarily on these efforts:

Punctuality

Efficiency

Etiquette

And generally trying to achieve the job to hand, to the highest standard possible, via the path of least resistance (the easiest, most logical, way).

I have a driving licence.

In terms of skills and Experience.

I first got my chainsaw ticket in 2016 whilst working doing landscaping. Quickly learnt that I enjoyed removing old trees and that tree surgery was the one for me.

At the time however I was quite young and had little experience, wasn't able to get a job and went back to collage studying agriculture, and then games development at CRC.

During this time period I laboured for a few trades people around the Cambridge area cash in hand. Mostly landscaping, sometimes construction.

In 2018 I moved up to Scotland, staying in the Highlands, I got a job with Boreal forestry. During this job we did a lot of work for the forestry commission. Planting, spraying, felling and thinning. After a year I moved down to Dorset.

In 2019 I was working for a company called Knighton Countryside management. In aims of bettering my position I put myself through my climbing ticket. Then seemingly got punished for not letting them rope me into a long contract by letting them pay. And soon after left the job.

Soon after that I started sub contracting for two local arborist businesses down in Dorchester area.

TOLLER TREE CARE and Thomas Lily Tree care.

With these two domestic companies I have learnt about domestic arb jobs. Including reductions, working on trees not usually forested, rigging, tracked chipper operation and driving, skid steer operation, and general site operations and exposure to the process of working on a domestic site.

My experience before sub contracting with KCM and up in Scotland taught me a lot about chainsaw operation, land clearance, and more commercial arb work.

Some point last year I took on my own job, which involved removing a long hedge of about 30 conifers from an air bnb. I insured myself and rented a tracked timber wolf, chipped on site and employed an experience mate to come help me tackle the workload. We spent one day in site together and I spent another day there with the cleanup.

This experience taught me alot about planning my work, and understanding the stress involved in organising work for my employers. Which is always a good experience to have.

However for now I still have plenty to learn and tickets to qualify etc. And want to continue to develope my skills. Preferably in the Cambridge area.

I drive an Isuzu Grafter NKR flatbed 3.5 Ton and am willing to use it for work if helpful.

I'm a hard worker, and I'm willing to give my very best to an employer that can give me regular work.

Willing to relocate to: Cambridge - -

Work Experience

Referance - Toller Tree Care

Toller Tree Care - Dorchester March 2019 to Present

Ian Geddes at TTC has been providing me with work and knowledge for a year and a half now. Has really taken me under his wing when I was new to the area and has continued to teach and train me in the domestic arb sector.

With TTC and Thomas lily I have undertaken a variety of different domestic jobs. For a large range of clientel. I have learned lots about chipping, and I have over time become TTC's Go-To when they need an extra groundie for the team. Which im proud of.

Forestry Operative

Boreal Forestry - Inverness January 2019 to October 2019

Tree planting, Chemical Application, thinning and clearance undertook on forestry commission and private sites.

Landscaper

various agency work, private buisnesses - Cambridge January 2015 to November 2018

Worked for a variety of soft and hard Landscaping buisnesses, first intending on doing gardening, then thinking about construction, before discovering hard landscaping and getting my cs30,31, and deciding I wanted to move into Arb, which has been my primary focus since.

Knighton countryside Management

Z - Dorchester

December 2009 to September 2010

When I first relocated to dorchester I got a job with KCM, I enjoyed the work but soon came round to multiple health and safety and communication issues for me at this company which didnt work for me, I enjoyed the work, but did not enjoy my time here.

Correct dates are 2019, however this is intended to be last on the list, which is sorted by date.

Education

GCSE or equivalent in Art

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in Physics

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in Maths

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in Biology

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in Chemistry

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in ICT

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in English

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in Geography

Cambridge

GCSE or equivalent in Religious studies

Cambridge

Diploma of Higher Education in Video Game Development

Cambridge

Skills

- · Ground Clearance
- Lawn Care
- Mowing
- Tree Climbing & Aerial Rescue (Less than 1 year)
- Tree felling (3 years)
- Labouring (5 years)

Certifications and Licenses

CScs 30/31

Felling and cross cutting and chainsaw maintenance

PA1, PA6 Spraying

Present

Cs 38 Aerial Rescue,

Present

Accessing a tree using a rope and harness.

Cscs

April 2020

Provisional

Additional Information

Qualifications - GCSE

- A ICT
- A Physics
- B Maths
- B English Literature
- A English Language
- B Bio and chem
- B Art
- C Geography
- B Religious Studies

ICT diploma